[
  {
    "question": "What is an <strong>arm's length transaction</strong>?",
    "answer": "An arm's length transaction is a transaction in which the parties involved are not inclined toward making voluntary concessions to each other."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define <strong>credit analysis</strong>.",
    "answer": "A credit analysis is an investigation of a loan applicant's ability to repay a potential loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes debt service?<br />&nbsp;(1) The making of mortgage payments by the borrower.<br />&nbsp;(2) The initiation of a mortgage loan.",
    "answer": "Which of the following best describes debt service?<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) The making of mortgage payments by the borrower.</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) The initiation of a mortgage loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "<strong>Gross debt service ratio</strong> is equal to the percentage of ______ income that is the maximum amount a mortgagor is allowed to pay ________ in principal, interest, and _______ taxes.",
    "answer": "Gross debt service ratio is equal to the percentage of <strong>gross</strong> income that is the maximum amount a mortgagor is allowed to pay <strong>annually</strong> in principal, interest, and <strong>property</strong> taxes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The percentage of lending value which determines the maximum loan available is known as the <strong>loan-to-value ratio</strong>.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "The percentage of lending value which determines the maximum loan available is known as the <strong>loan-to-value ratio</strong>.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a <strong>safety margin</strong>?",
    "answer": "A safety margin ensures that the net operating income (NOI) of a property is sufficient to cover the required mortgage payments."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a <strong>subprime mortgage</strong>?",
    "answer": "A subprime mortgage is a mortgage that is granted to a loan candidate who is considered high-risk due to a combination of poor or limited credit rating, non-verifiable income, previous consumer proposal, and/or bankruptcy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define <strong>mortgage loan default insurance</strong>.",
    "answer": "Mortgage loan default insurance insures the lender in the event where the borrower cannot make their loan payments."
  },
  {
    "question": "The period in time between the date mortgage funds are advanced and the beginning of the first payment period is known as the _______ _______ ________.",
    "answer": "The period in time between the date mortgage funds are advanced and the beginning of the first payment period is known as the <strong>interest adjustment period</strong>."
  },
  {
    "question": "Finish the following sentence:<br />&nbsp;<strong>Lending value</strong> is:",
    "answer": "a long term conservative estimate of the value of the property pledged as security for a loan."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an <strong>arm's length transaction</strong>?",
    "answer": "A transaction in which both interested parties act independently and in their own self-interest and where neither party is subject to pressure or undue influence from the opposing party."
  }
]